你被监视着
You are being watched.
政府有一套秘密系统
The government has a secret system--
一台每时每刻都在监控你的机器
a machine that spies on you every hour of every day.
联系系统管理员
[!]检测到异常情况
[!]转换探试行动
归入不相关号码
[!]检测到异常情况
[!]转换探试行动
归入不相关号码
来源:相关
执行
相关
催化剂靛蓝
调取任务数据
获取档案文件 催化剂 靛蓝
他问太多问题了
He's been asking too many questions.
阿基诺  丹尼尔
活动中
组织:北极光
任务:已被篡改
监管人:已被篡改
怎么处理
How do we deal with it?
看来我们手头有解决方案
Seems to me we have the solution at hand.
听着  你找错人了
Listen, you've got the wrong guy.
你只要
You just need to--
执行人  催化剂靛蓝
名字:已被篡改
社保号码:已被篡改
出生日期:已被篡改
邮政信箱:已被篡改
催化剂靛蓝
调取任务数据
定位执行人
调动卫星
德国柏林
获取GPS定位
定位执行人
最大化 执行人已定位
位置:德国柏林
实时
谢谢
Danke schoen.
干嘛跟踪我们
抱歉  我不懂德语
I'm sorry, I don't speak German.
有问题吗
没事  我想这只是个误会
No, I-I think it's just a misunderstanding.
没问题
他们骚扰你了吗
Are these men bothering you?
我很乐意拘留他们
I'd be happy to detain them.
不用了  谢谢
No. Thank you.
我想只是搞错了
I think it's just a mistake.
我有点赶时间
Listen, I'm in a bit of a hurry.
打电话给贝克缇  叫他们马上转移
美国人找上我们了
跪下
抱歉
我说了  我有点赶时间
发现贝克缇了没有
Any sign of our guy Bekhti?
没
No.
我刚才不得不把找到他的大好机会给毙了
And I just had to shoot our best chance of finding him.
我没路指给你了  肖
I can't take you anywhere, Shaw.
他刚想打给贝克缇了  我拿到部分号码了
Well, he was calling Bekhti. I got a partial number.
八位数
Eight digits.
你就不能等他拔完号再开枪吗
Couldn't you have shot him after he finished dialing?
查你的吧
Run it down, all right?
贝克缇正在搞的东西
Whatever Bekhti's into,
让这些人不惜杀死警察也要保密
these guys were willing to kill a cop to protect it.
贝克缇的手机信号就在我们下边
Bekhti's cell phone signal is right below us.
距地面约十几米
40, maybe 50 feet above the street.
可能是顶楼
Probably the top floor.
来吧
Here we go!
好了
All right.
不是这间
Wrong apartment.
加油吧
Go fish.
好了  正中
All right, we got a winner.
阿瓦士
Ahnaz.
你真让我失望
You disappoint me.
瞧瞧你  塑性炸药有了
Look at you, you got Semtex.
手机引爆装置也有了
You have a cell phone detonator.
让我看看
Let me see that.
还有铯
And cesium.
约半斤  他们在制作脏弹
Half a pound. They're making a dirty bomb.
有何计划
What's the plan?
完成了
一小时后出发
没时间了  我打给主控者
There's no time. I'm calling Control.
我是催化剂  代号"靛蓝"
Yeah, this is catalyst. Passphrase "Indigo".
说吧  靛蓝
Go ahead, Indigo.
请求批准行动
Request permission to engage.
直接出击
Direct action.
同意
Green light.
窗户都关着吗
They still have the windows closed?
应该是的
As far as I can tell.
你知道除你之外还有谁
You know the only other people crazy enough
会疯狂到用毒气吗  肖
to use the gas besides you, Shaw?
俄罗斯人
Russians.
[俄国]联邦安全局的俄罗斯疯子
Crazy FSB Russians.
你以为我哪儿来的灵感
Where do you think I get it?
第一个正中
We have our first winner.
第二个
Number two.
三个
There's three.
人人影视
YYeTs.com
原创翻译 双语字幕
仅供学习 禁止用于任何商业盈利行为
更多影视更新
请登陆www.YYeTs.com
翻译：Nonopig 麦结 面条打包子 油炸电风扇 天朝直属
特效：WiLL    时间轴：烟幕迟迟   擦擦   Jessie
翻译&校对&后期&总监：阿好
我取下铯了
I've removed the cesium.
肖  怎么回事
Shaw, what happened?
帮把手  科尔
A little help, Cole.
我看不到
I can't--
我看不到他  只有
I can't see him. Just--
发现什么了
What do you have?
还在找
Still looking.
我看不到他  肖
I don't see him, Shaw.
我还是没找到他
I-I still don't have him.
冷静
Calm down.
给我点有用的
Give me something I can use.
好的  等等
Okay, wait.
别动
Don't move.
三点钟方向
Your 3 o'clock!
现在
Now.
萨姆  你还好吗
Sam, you okay?
拉响火警  然后到大街上
Pull the fire alarm and head down to the street.
你要干什么
What are you gonna be doing?
取回子弹
Getting my bullets back.
我们从没来过  记得吗
We were never here, remember?
贝克缇电线组装得太粗糙了
Bekhti's wiring was a bit rough.
我帮他们改好了
I fixed it for them.
你真好
That's nice of you.
你自己走啊
You're making your own way out.
确定不需要人陪吗
Sure you don't want some company?
干嘛  你要给我介绍
Why, you know anybody?
该见时再见
I'll see you when I see you.
那就明天见
I'll see you tomorrow.
哪里
Where?
纽约
New York City.
主控者来电话了  我们有新号码了
Control called. We got another number.
看来就像你说的  号码从不停止
I guess it's like you said. They never stop coming.
-纽约怎么样  -冷
- How was New York? - Cold.
我今晚跟威尔森会面
I'm meeting with Wilson tonight.
你什么时候改送快递了
Since when do you make deliveries?
我来城里开个会
I was in town for a meeting.
想着我得来恭喜一下我的最佳特工
Thought I'd congratulate my best operator.
说说看
Tell me this.
我们雇你不是因为你拆弹强过引爆吗
Don't we pay you to disarm bombs rather than set them off?
《纽约时报》
恐怖分子藏匿处爆炸造成伤亡
是我决定的  我们找到了铯
My call. We had the cesium.
这应该是掩盖痕迹的最佳方式
Seemed like the best way to cover our tracks.
谢了  私下说说
Thank you. Unofficially.
有新号码
Your new number.
我还在盯着咱们的新号码
I've still got eyes on our new number.
他绕了一小时圈子了  科尔
He's been walking in circles for an hour, Cole.
我有点无聊了
I'm getting a little bored.
给我讲讲故事吧
Tell me a story.
詹姆斯・梅瑟
James Mercer.
在特种部队服役过四年
Did four in the corps.
后来被开除军籍
A dishonorable discharge.
投身民兵运动
Graduates to the militia movement.
一周前
And then a week ago,
一个海外账户给他电汇了一万
he gets wired 10k from an offshore account,
他搬去了皇后区
and moves to Queens.
我猜探索者认为他不是
I'm guessing research doesn't think he's here
来看百老汇的
for a Broadway show.
科尔  我可能暴露了
Cole, I think I've been made.
九点方向  西装帅哥
9:00, good-looking guy in a suit.
你确定他不是在欣赏你吗
You sure he's not just checking you out?
你可忘带防毒面具了  肖
Forgot your gas mask, Shaw.
好吧  虚惊一场
All right, false alarm.
有电话
Incoming.
梅瑟接到一个电话
Mercer's getting a call.
时间到  明天就是大日子
It's time. Tomorrow's the big day.
我们得看看这家伙的电脑  今晚
We need to get a look at this guy's computer tonight.
你可能得出来走走了
You may even have to get out of the van.
你有问题吗
Is something wrong with you?
你不是还在为那位斯陶德姑娘朝思暮想吧
You're not still pining for that girl in STAAD.
你不好奇探索者是从哪里得到号码的吗
You ever wonder where research gets the numbers?
-不  -为什么
- No. - Why?
因为我并不是为探索者工作
Because I don't work for research.
你有想过他们可能会犯错吗
Did you ever think they could be wrong sometimes?
就像圣何塞的那个家伙  阿基诺
Like that guy in San Jose. Aquino.
两年前
Two years ago.
他是那么的  困惑
He was... so confused.
-你还记得他怎么说吗  -记得
- You remember what he said? - I do.
因为
Because...
当时是我下手杀的他
I'm the one that killed him
而你只是通过摄像头看着
while you just watched on your little camera.
我还记得
I also remember...
他试图把核离心机的设计
that he was trying to sell designs
卖给黎巴嫩真主党
for a nuclear centrifuge to Hezbollah.
你查到了资金
And you tracked the money trail.
探索者对阿基诺的看法是对的
Research was right about Aquino.
他们永远都是对的
Like they're always right.
你怎么敢肯定他们永远都是对的
How can you be so sure that they are never wrong
你连他们是谁都不知道
if you have no idea who they even are...
也不知道他们从哪里得到的号码
or where they get these numbers?
我很清楚他们从哪里得到这些号码  科尔
I know exactly where they get those damn numbers from, Cole,
你也心知肚明
and so do you.
从他们对人严刑施虐的小黑屋里
From a dark room somewhere where they hurt people badly.
我们从不问探索者的号码从何而来
And the reason we don't ask where research gets its numbers from
是因为探索者从不出错
is because research is never wrong.
这次就错了
Well, they were this time.
你干蠢事了  是吧
You did something stupid, didn't you?
我给局里一个朋友打了电话
I called on one of my friends from the agency,
让她追踪资金
asked her to trace the money.
资金来源不是黎巴嫩真主党
Those transfers didn't come from Hezbollah.
是来自于美国政府
They came from the US government.
阿基诺是在做保密工作
Aquino was doing something covert,
但他是为了我们
but he was doing it for us.
我打了电话给主控者  威尔森
I called Control, Wilson.
我要求内部调查
I mean, I've requested an internal investigation.
我不会把你牵扯进来的  我保证
I will keep you out of it, I promise.
你对威尔森说了
You talked to Wilson?
是
Yeah.
梅瑟行动了
Mercer's on the move.
我们还有活儿要干
And we still have a job to do...
记得吗
remember?
好了  我进去了
All right. I'm in.
太简单了
That was easy.
有发现吗
Anything?
这不对劲
This is not right.
梅瑟跟一些联系人有邮件往来
Mercer's got a bunch of emails from some contacts--
都是退役军人
ex-military.
有那些联系人的名字吗
Do you have the name of the contacts?
有
Yeah.
是我们
They're us.
这些文件全是我们的名字
Our names are all over these files.
这是陷阱  快跑
肖  肖
Shaw? Shaw!
我们得离开  快
We need to move. Now.
有点难了
That's gonna be tough.
好了  来
All right, come on.
-抱歉  -不不不  别说话
- I'm sorry. - No, no, no, don't talk.
好了
All right.
我要打电话给主控者
Look, I'm gonna call Control, and, uh...
我们会救你
we're gonna get you some help.
我是想保护你
I was trying to get your back.
你一直想当英雄啊
Always trying to be the hero, huh?
不
No.
只当你的
Just yours.
二队  进去
Second team, head in.
肖
Shaw...
听着  我叫约翰
Listen. My name is John.
我是来帮你的
I'm here to help you.
三队  就位
Team three, move into position.
这里是二队  她好像有支援
This is team two. I think she may have backup.
还有一个人
There's some other guy in he--
所有小队报告  有没有杀掉那个女人
All teams, check in. Did you kill the woman or not?
威尔森
Wilson?
怎么样
Yes?
碰上点麻烦
We got a problem.
她跑了
I lost her.
我可不认为这只是点麻烦  威尔森
I would say that's a little more than a problem, Wilson.
我们搞定了科尔
We took care of Cole.
肖开枪逃跑了
Shaw managed to shoot her way out.
我损失了一个小队  场面有点难看
I lost a full team. It's a bit of a mess.
那真是  不幸
That's...unfortunate.
等一下
Just a moment.
这是您十点国务会议时要用的全部资料
That's everything you need for your 10:00 AM with state.
您还有别的需要吗
Will you need anything else?
没了  谢谢你  梅女士
No, thank you, Miss May.
祝你晚上愉快
Have a nice evening.
您也是  先生
You too, Sir.
那你的意思是
So you're telling me
那位危险的特工已经逃脱
we've got a lethal operative off the leash
她知道是我们杀了她的搭档
who's aware we terminated her partner
还想杀她
and tried to do the same to her
她还掌握了一些情况
and who may have information
足以危害到我们整个项目
which endangers our entire project.
情况就是这样  先生
That seems to be the situation, Sir.
首先  她要找地方休整
First, she'll be looking to regroup.
交通工具  武器  藏匿地点
Transportation, weapons, a place to hide.
但我们有一项优势
But we may have an edge.
什么优势
What's that?
我肯定射伤她了
I'm pretty sure I clipped her.
今晚想要什么  小妞
What you need tonight, girl?
我只需要一点光明
You know, I just need a little bit of daylight.
阳光[毒品俚语]
Sunshine.
明白
I got you.
等等
Hold on!
路易斯
Lewis?
你个傻冒跑这儿来
If your dumb ass is here,
那谁站街角啊
who the hell is out on the corner?
你跟鱼比过瞪眼睛吗
You ever have a staring contest with a fish?
什么
What?
鱼没有眼皮
No eyelids.
再努力也没用  对吧
Kinda pointless, right?
就像你想去拿那把猎枪一样
Like you reaching for that scattergun.
退后
Back up.
好的  来  路易斯
Okay, there, Lewis.
把你的朋友绑到暖气片上去
I'm gonna need you to ziptie your friend to the radiator.
绑紧了
Nice and tight.
路易斯  我需要一些东西
Lewis, I'm gonna need some things.
止痛药  剃须刀片
Painkillers, razor blades,
如果有没纱布  那就拿毛巾来
and if... there's no gauze, then towels.
空心弹
Hollow point.
狗娘养的
Son of a bitch!
我看过这样的枪伤
Seen shots like that before.
一旦打进内脏
You're gut shot.
你就完了
You're done.
你最好希望不会
You better hope not,
因为如果我开始失去意识
'cause if I start to lose consciousness,
我会先打死你
I'm shooting you first.
坐下  路易斯
Sit down, Lewis.
你以前做过吗
Have you done this before?
你很熟练
You're pretty good at it.
我曾经在医学院待过一阵
I was in med school for a bit.
你是医生
You're a doctor?
不是
No.
加入了海军陆战队
Joined the marines.
原来我更擅长杀人
Figured I was better at killing people
而非治人
than fixing them.
我马上就要失去意识了
I'm about to lose consciousness,
所以
so, uh...
我要你把自己和你朋友绑在一起  好吗
I need you to ziptie yourself along with your friend, okay?
我就知道你是个傻瓜  路易斯
I always knew you was an idiot, Lewis.
你好啊
Hey, you.
这枪不错
Nice piece.
你他妈到底是谁  来闹事的坏蛋吗
Who the hell you supposed to be, some kinda badass?
不全是
Not really.
我有所谓的第二轴人格障碍[反社会型]
I have what's called an Axis II personality disorder.
那是什么意思
What's that supposed to mean?
意思是说下手杀掉你和你朋友时
It means when I kill you and your friends,
我会毫无感觉
I'm not really gonna feel anything.
你要杀我
You gonna kill me?
你才几斤几两  上百斤吗
You weight what, hundred pounds?
9毫米子弹  重约35克
9mm round weighs about a quarter of an ounce.
就能搞定了
It gets the job done.
你的枪是点45口径的  小妞儿
But your gun's a .45, little girl.
我说的是备用枪
I was talking about my backup piece.
路易斯  走吧
Lewis, go.
如果你告诉别人我的事
If you tell anybody about me...
我就会找到你
I will find you.
肖是最出色的  我亲自训练的
Shaw is one of our best. Trained her myself.
你找不到她的  除非她自愿被找到
You're not gonna find her until she wants to be found.
我们要知道她的计划
We need to know her game plan.
肖会继续查阿基诺的事
Is Shaw going to look into the Aquino situation,
还是会来追杀我们复仇
or simply come after us for revenge?
都会
Both.
她擅长兼顾多项任务  我们雇她正是为此
She's a multitasker. It's why we hired her.
我们要追查科尔在中情局的联系人
We need to track down Cole's contact in the CIA.
我已经查到了  她叫维罗妮卡・辛科莱
I'm already on it. Her name is Veronica Sinclair.
你发现了什么  搭档
What did you find, partner?
你好
Hello?
你好  维罗妮卡
Hello, Veronica.
我想和你聊聊迈克尔・科尔
I wanna talk to you about Michael Cole.
你是谁
Who is this?
你告诉他的事情
Whatever you told him...
让他丢了性命
may have gotten him killed.
拜托  我不能被卷入此事
Please. I can't be involved in this.
要么你来见我  要么我去追查你
Well, you either meet me or I track you down.
那可不会是你想要的
And that is not something that you want.
曼哈顿  斯福克酒店
Manhattan, the Suffolk Hotel,
1458房间  明晚5点
Room 1458, 5:00 PM tomorrow.
我会去的
I'll be there.
肖
Shaw.
猜到你早晚会给我电话
Figured you'd be calling me sooner or later.
你应该自首  萨姆
You should really come in, Sam.
你清楚你是逃不掉的
You know there's no point in running from us.
我会自首  但只对老大
I'll turn myself in, but only to the boss.
-我要见主控者  -我可不同意
- I wanna meet Control. - I don't think so.
我叫老大过来  你去杀他
I call my boss, you try to kill him.
这会让我很难堪的
It's very embarrassing for me.
我将会面地点发给你
I will send you the location,
你确保他会出现
you make sure he's there,
否则我公开阿基诺的档案
or else I go public with the Aquino files.
-什么时候  -今晚
- When? - Tonight.
威尔森  别让我等
And, Wilson, don't keep me waiting.
-你好  维罗妮卡  -进来吧
- Hello, Veronica. - Come in.
有人跟踪你吗
Any chance you were followed?
我觉得没有  不过
I don't think so, but...
我从训练营毕业后一直没出过外勤
I haven't been in the field since I was at the farm.
你是萨姆  对吗
You're Sam, right?
迈克尔跟我说起过你
Michael talked about you.
他没告诉我你们是做什么事的
I mean, he didn't tell me about what you guys do or anything,
不过  他喜欢你
but...he liked you.
他怎么了
What happened to him?
被杀了
He was killed.
执行任务时
On a mission.
你对这些知道越少
The less you know about all of this,
就越安全
the safer you'll be.
但我要知道他到底告诉你什么了
But I do need to know what he talked to you about.
迈克发给我一些资金转账信息
Mike sent over details of wire transfers
是转给核电工程师丹尼尔・阿基诺的
to a nuclear engineer named Daniel Aquino.
这些资金看起来是从
They appeared to originate
黎巴嫩真主党名下的账户中发出的  但是
out of accounts affiliated with Hezbollah, but...
有人篡改了那些电子转账信息
someone had electronically spoofed the transfers.
我查到了
I was able to track down
真正转出资金的账户
the real originating accounts.
资金是从美国政府汇出的
They were out of the US government.
政府什么部门
Which part of the government?
隶属五角大楼的组织
A group out of the pentagon
名叫"情报支持行动处"
called the Intelligence Support Activity.
你听说过他们吗
Have you heard of them?
可以这么说
You could say that.
直到昨天  我还在为他们工作
Up until yesterday, I worked for them.
他们的预算资金是机密
Their budget's confidential,
但是  从五年前就开始了
but... it stretches back five years.
大笔金额都拨给了一个叫
Huge amounts coded to a project
"北极光"的项目
called "Northern Lights."
这是什么项目
What was the project?
我不知道
I don't know.
但阿基诺参与了这个项目
But Aquino was part of it.
他们建立了一个叫"探索者"的设备
They built a facility of some kind coded as research.
但我查不到
But I can't find
其他项目参与者的名字
the names of anyone else involved in the project.
麦克说阿基诺告诉了你
Mike said Aquino told you
他在北极光项目中联系人的名字
the name of his contact in Northern Lights.
你还记得吗
Do you remember it?
待在这儿
Stay here.
离窗户远一点
And keep away from those windows.
你来之前  维罗妮卡和我闲聊了一会儿
Veronica and I had a bit of a chat before you got here.
她非常  非常努力地回忆所有
She tried really, really hard to remember anything else
对我有帮助的事情  但是
that could help me, but...
她一无所知
she didn't know anything.
我看过你的档案  我是你的忠实粉丝
I read your file, and I'm kind of a big fan.
所以  我真的不想伤害你
So, I really don't wanna hurt you.
我只需要个名字
I just need the name.
看来你根本不知道自己卷入了什么  是吧
You really have no idea what you're caught up in, do you?
不知道你到底是在为谁工作
Who you're actually working for?
你真的相信那些号码来自关塔那摩吗
Did you honestly think the source of the numbers was Guantanamo?
某个可怜的出租车司机正被关在笼子里慢慢腐烂吗
Some sad taxi driver rotting away in a cage somewhere?
你应该知道
I mean, you should know
严刑拷打几乎从来问不出有用的信息
torture almost never produces good information.
几乎
Almost never.
可惜的是
Sadly,
我们时间有点紧
we are on a bit of a clock.
威尔森的人三小时前就开始寻找维罗妮卡了
Wilson's men started looking for Veronica here three hours ago.
现在
Now...
阿基诺受雇为一个极特殊的东西建造场所
Aquino was hired to build a home for something very special,
我想找的东西
something I wanna find.
所以告诉我他联系人的名字
So you're gonna tell me the name of his contact.
我的档案里有一点漏了
One of the things I left out of my file...
我对这种事其实乐在其中
I kind of enjoy this sort of thing.
我真高兴你这么说
I am so glad you said that.
我也是呢
I do too.
我们刚要开始亲近一下呢
And just when we were starting to really connect.
真抱歉
I'm sorry.
有点无礼  我知道
A little rude, I know.
我们很快会再有机会的
We'll do this again soon.
安全
Clear!
全部安全
All clear.
靛蓝锁定  还有第二目标
Indigo located. And the secondary.
什么指示
Instructions?
明白
Understood.
帮个忙行吗
Can you do me a favor?
这次别对我开枪行吗
Can you not shoot me this time?
-给我一个理由  -我不知道
- Give me a good reason. - I don't know.
我是好人噢
I'm a really nice person,
还有  那个
and, well... that.
可以吗
May I?
好吧
Okay.
可能是乌头碱
It's probably acontine.
可以用阿托品解毒  如果我失手的话
You can counteract it with atropine...in case I bump it.
我们用的剂量  最多撑四分钟
The dose we use, you've got about four minutes.
所以除非你身上带着阿托品
So unless you've got some atropine on you,
否则别失手
don't bump it.
我的朋友想和你聊聊
I got a friend who wants to talk to you.
我为什么要和你的朋友聊呢
Why would I wanna talk to one of your friends?
你有别的地方可去吗
You got somewhere better to be?
你好  肖女士
Hello, Ms. Shaw.
你可以叫我哈罗德
You can call me Harold.
你是负责人
You're the man in charge?
不  没有负责人
No. No one's in charge.
我的朋友和我只是帮助需要帮助的人
My friend and I help people in trouble.
或许你们为威尔森工作  这是在跟我玩游戏
Or maybe you work for Wilson and this is all some kinda game.
坦白说  我从不擅长玩游戏
Honestly, I was never terribly good at games.
你为  至少曾经为
You work-- or at least you used to work--
一个秘密政府组织工作
for a secret government program
旨在预防涉及到
that prevents terrible things--
国家安全的恐怖袭击和犯罪活动
terrorist acts and crimes relevant to nation security.
你收到的消息
The information that you received
来自一群你称之为"探索者"的人
came from a group of people that you call "Research."
他们以两点著称
And it's notable for two reasons.
第一  从不出错
One, it's never wrong.
第二  只给号码
And two, it consists only of a number.
-这是  -你的号码
- This is-- - Your number.
还有科尔先生的
And Mr. Cole's.
我们没救出他  我为此深感遗憾
We were unable to save him, and for that, I'm sorry.
我们最初不了解
We didn't understand the exact nature
你们的准确情况
of your situation at first.
既然你们不是那个组织的
So if you're not part of the program...
那你们是谁
then who are you?
这么说吧  说到底
Let's just say that ultimately,
你我为同一实体工作
you and I work for the same entity.
而这一实体让你
And that entity wanted you
和你朋友去救我吗
and your friend over there to help me?
可以这么说
In a manner of speaking.
实际上  我们应该是唯一能救你的人
In truth, we're probably the only people who can help you.
既然你这么了解我的雇主
Well, if you know so much about my employers,
你一定也知道他们非常
then you must know that they are very...
非常善于找人
very good at finding people.
即使是你  也不能永远逃下去
Even you can't run forever.
我不需要永远
I don't need forever.
只要找到背后主使者
Just long enough to find the man behind the curtain,
那个下灭口命令的人
the one who gave the kill order.
你连他们组织的皮毛都伤不到
You won't even scratch the surface of their organization,
而你却会一直面临生命危险
and you'll still be in grave danger.
你掌握着谜题的一块
You hold a piece of a puzzle,
这秘密非常重要  他们为保护它不惜杀死
a secret so important that they were willing to kill
阿基诺博士  你朋友迈克尔・科尔  还有你
Dr. Aquino and your friend Michael Cole and yourself to protect it.
你所谓"探索者"那群人的真相
The truth about a group of people you call "Research".
科尔已经开始怀疑了
Something that Cole had begun to suspect.
-是什么  -他们根本不存在
- Which is what? - That they don't exist.
这个世界看上去和十年前一样
The world looks like it did ten years ago,
但实际上  已经截然不同了
but underneath, it's become very strange indeed.
一场无形的斗争已经开始
An invisible struggle has begun.
大多数知情者已经死了
Most of the people who knew this are already dead.
一切顺利的话  我希望你能免步后尘
All things being equal, I prefer you didn't join them.
如我所说  我们可以帮助你
So like I said... we're here to help you.
但首先  你得停止逃跑
But first, you need to stop running
因为你太内行了  我们跟不住你
because you're much too good at it and we can't keep up.
-躲藏不是我的风格  -那死亡是吗
- Hiding isn't my style. - But dying is?
因为在我看来  这是唯一的选项
Because, as I see it, that's your only option.
我没有什么朋友
You know, I never had many friends.
觉得对我没用
Didn't have much use for 'em.
科尔是唯一的例外
Cole was an exception.
他的命运不该那样
And he deserved better.
一个忠告
A word of advice for what it's worth.
去纠正这个世界的错误
Set out to correct the world's wrongs
往往结果只是错上加错
and you'll almost certainly wind up adding to them.
我的电话  如果你改变主意的话
My number, in case you change your mind.
谢了
Thanks.
不过免了  谢了
But no thanks.
该了结一切了  就今晚
It's time to end this. Tonight.
-把队伍准备好  -是  先生
- Get a team ready. - Yes, Sir.
你迟到了
You're late.
我本想问你怎么知道是我
I'd ask how you knew it was me,
不过我们雇你正是为此
but I guess that's what we pay you for--
在人群中找到对的人
picking the right person out of a crowd.
我当然想见见主控者
Of course I wanted to meet Control.
而你不是主控者  对吗
And you're not Control, now, are you?
很遗憾  不是
Sadly, no.
但你也只能找到我这一级了
But I'm as close as you're gonna get.
你置组织于危险之中
You'd really put the program in jeopardy
就为给你搭档报仇
just to avenge your partner?
我以为你这样的女人
I assumed a woman like you
应该会有更成熟的世界观呢
would have a more sophisticated world view.
你们雇我  是因为我基本上不在乎别人
You people hired me because I don't care about most people.
然而你们却杀死了
And then you went and killed
我唯一喜欢的人
the one person that I actually liked.
有道理
Fair enough.
当然   你也不该满怀怨恨地出现
Of course, you weren't supposed to be around to carry a grudge.
你想见面
You wanted to meet.
是想查明为什么我让威尔森
Was it to find out why I let Wilson
除掉你和你的搭档吗
target you and your partner?
还是只想杀了我
Or just to kill me?
无论哪个  我们都该换个隐秘点的地方
Either way, we should go somewhere more private.
或许你认为我很邪恶
You probably think I made a devil's bargain.
或许吧
And maybe I have.
但正是因为这个组织
But the program is the reason
我们才避免了再受重大袭击
we haven't had another major attack.
如果公众知道我们的所作所为
If the public knew about what we do,
我们就会失去这一能力
we'd lose that ability.
阿基诺呢
And Aquino?
同样  令人遗憾的决定
Again, a regrettable decision,
但却是必须的
but a necessary one.
没有人能置身于千百万国人的安危之上
No one life is above the safety of millions of Americans.
我每天都得做这种丑陋的算计
That's the ugly math that I have to deal with every day.
你应该最明白的
You of all people should understand that.
的确
I do.
我在你的位子上  也会做同样的事
And if I were in your place, I'd do the exact same thing.
我或许不再和这组织有关系了
I may not be in the program anymore,
但是我
but I--
我仍理解它有多重要
I still understand how important it is.
那为什么要打打杀杀的
Then why the cloak and dagger?
科尔关于阿基诺案的调查
Cole's research on the Aquino case.
我想亲自交给你
I wanted to give it to you personally.
为什么不交给威尔森
Why not give it to Wilson?
你雇了科尔这种人
You can't hire people like Cole
就不要指望他们会乖如羔羊
and expect them to act like sheep.
我只会服从命令
Now, I know how to follow orders.
但科尔非常聪明
But Cole was just brilliant,
相信凡事必有因
and he believed in the cause.
威尔森清楚这点
And Wilson knew that.
你本可以警告他  或者警告我
You know, you could've warned him, or even me.
但你却直接下格杀令
But instead, you placed a kill order
必除之而后快
like we were some kinda problem to be solved.
你的搭档违反了规定
Your partner broke the rules.
你跟他一样对此纠结不已
You're on the hook for that as much as he was.
然后你就华丽丽地搞砸了任务
And then you screwed that up in such a spectacular fashion.
我怎么能在这么重要的事上信任这个蠢货
How could I trust this idiot with something so important?
赫什说得对
Hersh was right.
你是名优秀的士兵
You are a good soldier.
你并不是想复仇
You didn't want revenge.
你是想保护组织
You wanted to protect the program.
优秀的士兵会兼顾
A good soldier does both.
放她走
Let her go.
清理一下
Let's clean this up.
? You can holler, you can wail ?
? You can swing, you can flail ?
? You can like a broken sail ?
? But I'll never give you up ?
? If I ever give you up ?
? My heart will surely fail ?
你是优秀的特工  抱歉  肖
You were a good operator. Sorry, Shaw.
? And after all, God can keep my soul ?
? England have my bones ?
? But don't ever give me up ?
? I could never get back up ?
? When the future starts so slow ?
这位女士直接昏倒在街上
Lady just passed out in the street,
心肺复苏无效
unresponsive to CPR.
急救人员一到场就宣布死亡了
EMT's called it as soon as they arrived.
你认为这就是凶杀了
So this looks like a homicide to you?
当然  这个年纪的女人  没有一点伤痕
Sure. Woman her age, not a mark on her.
我觉得很可疑
I thought it suspicious.
可没想到凶案组能出现
Can't expect the task force to show up.
我们就在附近  弗莱明警官
We were in the neighborhood, Officer Fleming.
这位大概药物过量或者心脏骤停
Yeah, we're probably looking at an overdose or cardiac arrest.
好的  但为了确定  我们得
Yeah, but, I mean, just to make sure, we ought to--
你不如去给自己买杯咖啡吧
Why don't you grab yourself a coffee?
我们来处理好吧
We got this, okay?
谢谢你的帮助
Thanks for your help.
又到满月抽风时  验尸官办公室忙不过来了
It's a full moon. Coroner's office is swamped.
把她运到下城区行吗
You mind getting her downtown?
听你的  警探
Whatever you say, Detective.
搭把手好吗
Little help here?
? You can holler, you can wail ?
? You can blow what's left of my right mind ?
? You can swing, you can flail ?
她是性感
She may be hot,
但我不想再看见那妞儿了
but that's one broad I never wanna see again.
永永远远
I mean, ever!
你们从没告诉我她既危险  又疯狂
You guys never told me she was dangerous and crazy!
可怕的组合
Bad combo.
怎么了
What happened?
我给她注射了阿托品和杜冷丁让她保持昏迷
I gave her the atropine and some demerol to knock her out.
但是她在半路就醒了
But she woke up on the drive over
差点杀了我
and almost killed me!
瞧  瞧我脖子上的瘀伤
Look--look at this bruise on my neck.
所以我加大了量
So I gave her some more.
多大量  陶先生
How much more, Mr. Tao?
我不知道  你瞧我像医生吗
I don't know. I look like a doctor to you?
天啊
Man.
这烂事的报酬可真不够
I so don't get paid enough for this crap.
我们根本没付报酬  里昂
We don't pay you anything, Leon.
我得闪远点了  两位
I'm gonna widen the distance, fellas.
你们试试吧
You take your chances.
死亡会让人口渴
Dying can make you thirsty.
作为守护天使
For Guardian Angels,
你们两位来得也太迟了
you two were a bit late to the party.
你的雇主希望你死
Your employers wanted you dead.
所以你死了
So now you are.
我想里昂忘记了
I guess Leon forgot the instructions
要搜你身的指令
about patting you down.
肖女士  我们是帮你的
Ms. Shaw, we're on your side.
我想我们已经证明你可以信任我们
I feel like we've proven that you can trust us.
信任未免过了
Trust is overrated.
把电话给我
Toss me your phones.
如我上次所说
Like I said before...
如果你改变主意的话
just in case you change your mind.
此电话大大有惊喜  打打试试吧
? You can holler, you can wail ?
? You can blow what's left of my right mind ?
? You can swing, you can flail ?
她真叫人印象深刻
Well, she certainly makes an impression.
你觉得她会帮我们叫出租车吗
Do you think she'll call us a taxi?
? You can holler, you can wail ?
? You can blow what's left of my right mind ?